I want to talk about the name of Jesus.
The name of Jesus.
I know we began in the month of April
and you'll allow me to focus on this
lesson
uh checking on what I call a believer's
authority.
It is prudent that anytime you teach
spirituality, you teach it with a lot of
balance.
We say that we can grow a Christ
consciousness but we can equally grow a
demonic consciousness.
Uh I was listening to one psychiatrist
and he said there is a part of the brain
in every man. There is a part in your
brain that is very key in programming
your life and it is pattern to respond
to what you keep on hearing and what you
keep on confessing.
There is a part in your brain that tries
to program your mind to become what you
actually listen and what you actually
confess repeatedly.
And I began now to understand why uh
that these two consciousness can be uh
can be activated with a lot of bias. It
is key for there to be a balance to know
that we serve a powerful God but also to
understand that we are not ignorant of
the devices of the enemy. And today um
we began by checking on the believer's
authority. That's the language of
salvation. The very life of God is
already in you. Last Sunday we checked
on the mystery of bar abbas the language
of the law of substitution.
But when we go to the same book in the
book of Colossians I believe now chapter
number two we were looking at was it
Colossians 2 and verse 13 uh whereby we
saw that he publicly disarmed he
publicly disarmed yeah having disarmed
having disarmed Colossians 2:15
having disarmed publicly
uh yes everybody read having disarmed
principalities ities and powers. He made
a public spectacle of them, triumphing
over them in it.
The writer of the book of Colossians is
Paul.
There are certain expressions that Paul
brought into vicinity with a lot of
military understanding.
And so when we read them, unless we have
the military background of what this
meant, we may not fully understand what
this scripture means. And so I want us
to tie this with the book of Philippians
chapter number two from verse 1 to 11.
We are going to read it in NKJV and then
we are going to read it in message
version. Hallelujah. Amen. We're going
to read them in those two versions. Um
uh uh yes nobody should be standing
anywhere. There are many seats. So let
let people be settled. Therefore if
there is any consolation in Christ, if
any comfort of love, if any fellowship
of the spirit, if any affection and
mercy,
fulfill my joy by being likeminded,
having the same love, being of one
accord, of one mind. Look, let nothing
be done through selfish ambition or
conceit, but in loneliness of mind, let
each esteem others better than himself.
Let each of you look out not only for
his own interest, but also for the
interest of others.
Everybody read, "Let this mind be in you
which was also in Christ Jesus." Let's
look at six. Let us all read. Who being
in the form of God did not consider it
robbery to be equal with God,
but made himself of no reputation,
taking the form of a bond servant. If
you are, if you are, this is the
precursor word that is going to open all
the realities of this verse.
taking the form of a bondervant and
coming in the likeness of men.
And being found in appearance as a man,
he humbled himself and became obedient
to the point of death, even the death of
the cross. You can SEE THE EMPHASIS. NOT
JUST ANY DEATH. He became obedient even
to the death of the cross.
Let's look at nine. Therefore, everybody
read, "God has highly exalted him and
given him the name."
Now, this is a the Bible says, "Not a
name."
There is an article the name
we'll come to THAT WHICH IS ABOVE EVERY
name
that at the name so we now know the name
of Jesus
every knee should
not shall
should
remember those guys who read the
constitution
and say the people may.
You didn't see that thing. If the people
may, so that means grammar is good. What
does the Bible say? That every knee
should bow. So there are knees in heaven
and of those on earth
and of those we are talking about knees.
>> There are also knees under the earth.
But the Bible says at the mention of the
name Jesus they should bow.
Let's continue.
And that every tongue
should confess that Jesus
Christ is Lord
to the glory of God the Father.
There is always an arrangement of
Jesus Christ,
the Lord Jesus Christ. And now there's
another one here. Jesus Christ is Lord.
It's not a confusion. It's not a
confusion. So let's read this now in
message Bible beginning from verse 5.
Let us read in message Bible. message
has a way of expounding it. Message
Bible.
Think of yourselves the way Christ Jesus
thought of himself.
He had equal status with God but didn't
think so much of himself that he had to
cling to the advantages of that status
no matter what. There's a time they told
him call for. He said no. He had just go
to six. He had the same status but he
never cling to those advantages. He was
bound in the parameters of a human
being. Look at seven. Not all. When the
time came he SET ASIDE THE PRIVILEGES of
dity
and took ON THE STATUS OF A slave became
human.
Having become human stayed human. It was
an incredibly humbling process. He
didn't claim special privileges.
Instead, he lived a selfless obedient
LIFE AND THEN DIED a selfless obedient
death. And the worst kind of death at
that, a crucifixion.
Because of that obedience, God lifted
him high and honored him far beyond
anyone or anything ever.
So that all created beings in heaven and
on earth, even those long ago dead and
buried, will bow in worship before this
Jesus Christ
and call out in praise that he is the
master of all to the glorious honor of
God the Father.
There are five revelations that are very
key for one to know about Jesus. There
are five revelations that are very key
for one to know about Jesus. Number one,
it is important to know the revelation
of the virgin birth of Christ. The
virgin birth. It is important to know
the revelation of the virgin birth.
It was a very contended matter in the
early centuries whereby this is
something that had never happened. But
when we look at it, it was prophesied by
Isaiah that behold a virgin shall be
with a child. So we need to have the
revelation of the virgin birth because
it is out of the revelation of the
virgin birth that we talk about the
incarnation of God. God becoming man.
The incarnation of God. That is God
becoming man. The second thing is the
revelation of the man Jesus. The
revelation of the man Jesus. So we HAVE
THE THE PART OF the virgin birth.
How God became man in the womb of Mary.
In the womb of Mary. It is a revelation
and it has to be understood.
It is if we don't accept the virgin
birth then ideally we can never believe
that God became man. And there are many
people who don't believe that.
And then we have also to understand that
there is the revelation of the man
Jesus. The revelation of the man Jesus.
During the week I got time to glean on
the silent ears of Jesus between the age
of 12 to the age of 13. A good student
of scripture understands that we hear of
Jesus
uh when he was born. There is the
concept of Herod saying that children
less than these years should be killed.
The there is an angel that appeared to
Joseph. Jesus is taken to Egypt. And
then the the the Maggis come and they
worship him. And then after the
dedication and the and the circumcision
of Jesus, we we don't hear about him
again until age 12.
And the age 12 is a precursor for
scholars of scripture because the
natural way that a Jew raised their
children was by the time a son turned
five to six years, they were subjected
to the literature'ses of the Torah. And
they were not just supposed to read the
Torah, they were supposed to memorize
the Torah. Genesis, Exodus, Leviticus,
Numbers, and Deuteronomy. And so between
the age of five and six, the the the
teachers and and this exercise was
highly facilitated by the father. It was
the role of the father to teach his son
the Torah. That was the entry. And so
when they discovered that a son was wise
and had understanding and grasp over the
matters of the Torah, that son was taken
aside and he was subjected under a rabbi
and the lectures of that son was a
little bit advanced. And the MOMENT THAT
SONA NOW GREW, they presented him to the
temple to sit with rabbis and scribes. A
rabbi was a teacher of the law. A scribe
was an interpreter of the law like a
modern day lawyer. So these were men
that had experience with the law. And so
by the time Jesus was sitting in the
temple at the age of 12, it is automatic
he was in the school of rabbis
because he was interacting with elders
and MEN THAT HAD EXPERIENCE OF THE LAW.
And and and when you look at what they
call the Jewish Midrash,
the Jewish Midrash is a collection of
rabbitical interpretation of certain
scriptures. That's what they call the
Jewish Midrash is a collection of
rabbitical teachers that lived centuries
back. WHEN YOU ATTEND um um um a
synagogue or when you go to a Judaistic
temple, the way they teach is different
from how we teach a a a a RABBI WILL
QUOTE OTHER rabbis
and that's how they used to operate. But
when it came to Jesus, he reasoned with
the teachers of the law. the rabbis
reasoned WITH THEM BUT NEVER QUOTED any
rabbi
and that's WHY WHEN HE BEGAN TO TEACH
they said this man teaches with
authority
THE AUTHORITY THERE WAS THE ability to
EXPOUND ON SCRIPTURE WITHOUT REFERRING
TO THE midrash and the teachings of
other rabbi because he was the author
>> when he made the tooth to a mouse. He
said, "It is written of me." He opened
for Moses to ALL THE PROPHETS. BUT AS A
MAN JESUS, HE STILL SAT under rabbitical
order to be taught.
Between the age of 12 to the age of 30,
we hear nothing about Jesus. That's the
man Jesus. We hear NOTHING ABOUT JESUS.
BUT BY THE TIME HE'S PRESENTED TO THE
TEMPLE at the age of 12, we know the
story. The parents are looking for him.
And he comes and tells them, "I WAS IN
MY FATHER'S BUSINESS."
And we begin to see that this was not an
ordinary boy in the streets of
Jerusalem.
Even the people understood that he was
not an ordinary boy. And do you know
that is the last time we hear about
Joseph.
That's the last time we hear about
THE EARLY WRITINGS confirm that the
interpretation of Joseph being a
carpenter may not actually be the real
thing that Joseph was doing.
THE NAME CARPENTER there in the Greek
interpretation is mercenary. A man that
worked with rocks.
is a is a Gibbro called techno
something.
It means a man that works with rocks and
there has been
I know you you sang that song called
funo
and you see that that's the problem of
when certain literatures are taught from
tradition but not from revelation
you see the money the teachings of Jesus
were connected to the trade of Christ
many of the parables were connected to
the the the the system. When you look at
where Jesus lived, the coexisting
business was not carpentry. It was
mercenary work from limestone.
So in those days, it is believed that
Jesus possibly might have been a mason,
one that worked with rocks. That's why
he's called the rock of ages.
Pastor Ronnie, many of the teachings of
Christ, he never mentioned wood except
once. When he spoke about a speck in the
eye and a log, that's the only time he
spoke of wood,
he spoke of the stone that the builders
rejected became the most important
stone. He spoke about if you build upon
these sayings of mine, you are like a
wise man builder who build upon a rock
and his house actually was there.
Many of the teachings of Christ were on
agriculture and rocks.
So what even for Peter he changed his
name to a rock. Now of course we're not
going there. It is believed that Joseph
died
and Jesus BEING THE FIRSTBORN TOOK
responsibility of the family. He had
brothers and sisters. There were almost
seven in that family. There are other
children of Mary through Joseph. SO HE
MUST HAVE TAKEN CARE OF HIS family
through the work that he found his
father doing. Jesus as a man was not
pleasing.
He became the father at a very young age
taking care of the family.
IT IS ONLY THAT ACCORDING TO THE CULTURE
OF THE day you could not ascend to
priesthood assignment before you are 30.
AT 12, HE KNEW WHO HE WAS. BUT THERE WAS
A TEMPLATE IN THE SPIRIT THAT THE AGE 30
IS THE AGE of maturity for inheritance.
And heaven was quiet.
There are certain blueprints that heaven
honors.
When he clocked 30, HE HAD ENTERED the
Levitical age of legality to become a
Levite and a priest that could burn
incense in the altar of God. AT THE AGE
30 IS THE AGE when David became a king
of Israel.
He was ANOINTED AT 14, 15, 16 AS A KING.
BUT THE FINAL MANIFESTATION OF HIS
KINGSHIP HAPPENED AT 30. So David, so
Jesus is a priest. Jesus is a king. HE
MUST FOLLOW THE PATTERNS THAT ORDAINED
MEN INTO the office. It must be 30.
And that's why now he goes to the Jordan
to BE BAPTIZED AND HEAVEN opens and the
Holy Ghost comes down like a dove.
Immediately after that
WE NOW WE ARE NOW dealing with not just
the man Jesus we are dealing with
Emmanuel
God with us.
Are we still there?
When the Holy Spirit came for the first
time, we saw the the the organization of
the Trinity at play in one location
without contradiction.
The father spoke and said, "This is my
son." THE LANGUAGE SON there is
maturity.
ISAIAH GAVE US A PROPHECY AND SAID,
"Unto us a child is born."
WHEN THE CHILD WAS BORN, THERE WAS NO
UTTERANCE FROM THE FATHER.
>> THE ONLY UTTERANCE WAS, "HOW SHALL THIS
BE?" AND IT IS AN ANGEL WHO SAID, "THE
POWER OF THE MOST HIGH SHALL COME UPON
THEE, and you shall be WITH A CHILD."
HEAVEN NEVER SPOKE. IT WAS an angel that
kept on giving them direction. God loves
children, but God does not work with
children.
During circumcision, THE EIGHTH DAY,
HEAVEN NEVER SPOKE. It was two men,
Simeon and
this woman, Hannah. They're the ones WHO
SAID HANNAH PROPHETICALLY SHARED WHO
Jesus was. And Simeon Simeon SAID,
"BEHOLD, I HAVE SEEN the deliverance and
salvation of Israel because the Lord had
made a covenant that my eyes will not
close until I see the salvation and
deliverance." AND HANNAH WAS THE
INTERCESSOR WHO WAS interceding for the
arrival of THE MESSIAH. THEY SAW HIM
PROPHESIED and Mary kept the MATTER IN
HER HEART. BUT HEAVEN never spoke.
You'll be so surprised
that
Shi the time heaven spoke last. It was
in Malachi.
That was the time men had the voice of
God. It was in Malachi.
WHEN THEY SAW JOHN COMING, THEY THOUGHT
IT WAS HIM. He said, "I am the voice."
And they realized, "This is the voice of
the one that prepares the way." But the
people were waiting for the voice of God
again.
FOR 430 YEARS, God had not spoken
BECAUSE SOMETHING IS ABOUT TO SHIFT.
And that thing is in the book of Hebrews
FOR 400 YEARS. 430 heaven was quiet
BECAUSE IN SUNLIGHT TIMES, HEBREW
CHAPTER NUMBER ONE AND VERSE ONE.
Ron know this is your word.
IN SUNRISE TIME, GOD WHO AT VARIOUS
TIMES AND IN VARIOUS ways spoke PAST
TENSE IN TIME PAST TO THE FATHERS BY THE
PROPHETS. THAT'S A PATTERN. THAT'S THE
OLD TESTAMENT PATTERN. HE SPOKE BY THE
PROPHETS. HE'S NOW ABOUT TO SHIFT HOW HE
SPEAKS.
Now he CONTINUES AND SAYS, "HAS IN THESE
LAST DAYS," LOOK AT THE TENSES. HE SPOKE
TO THE PROPHETS. BUT IN THESE LAST DAYS,
HE HAS SPOKEN THROUGH WHO? TO US BY HIS
SON.
So if you ARE LOOKING FOR A PROPHET WHO
cannot point to the words of the son,
that man is speaking on his own.
>> IF YOU ARE GOING TO THE MOUNTAIN TO HEAR
GOD, GOD HAS ALREADY SPOKEN. HE WILL
TAKE YOU BACK TO THE WORDS OF ISLAM.
>> You know there's a lot of manufacturing
of the voice of God IF THEY DON'T MATCH
THE WORD. THIS IS HEBREW THAT THERE ARE
DAYS DRAMATICALLY GOD SPOKE THROUGH
EZEKIEL. THERE ARE DAYS HE SPOKE THROUGH
ISAIAH BUT HE KEPT QUIET FOR 430 YEARS.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT HE SAID? HE SAID, "THIS
IS MY SON with whom I'm WELL PLEASED
WITH. LISTEN TO HIM."
It is in Matthew.
OH, HE NEVER SPOKE WHEN JESUS WAS BORN.
GOD DOES NOT DEAL WITH CHILDREN. A CHILD
IS ANYONE THAT DEPENDS ON GOD. I have
children in my house.
They depend on me.
Even even offering I give them that's
how childish they are.
I give them offering to worship God.
But you know time is coming. Yesterday
my father had called me and he gave me
responsibilities
because you depend on your son
but you cannot depend on your child.
Now you can audit yourself where you
are. Can God depend on you?
That one even dictates your prayers.
When you look at the prayer list is
dependency.
The prayer of a son is not my will.
Lord, you can depend me with the
salvation of men. You I can bear that
assignment.
Jesus was maturing their prayer by
telling them the things you are asking
for. Even Gentiles are in NEED OF THE
PRAYERS YOU ARE MAKING OF FOOD, SHELTER,
those are prayers of children. And it
now tells them your father in heaven
knows YOUR FATHER. SO WHEN HE'S A
FATHER, YOU CAN EITHER BE A CHILD OR A
SON.
HE KNOWS YOU'RE IN NEED OF THEM. BUT
THEN HE TELLS THEM THERE ARE THINGS THAT
SOME SEEK IS NOT BREAD. IT'S NOT BUTTER.
PLEASE DON'T GET ME WRONG. THERE IS A
LEVEL WHEN YOU STEP IN SOME LEVELS. YOU
SEE THE PRESIDENT CANNOT PRAY FOR RENT.
BY HIM GETTING IN THE OFFICE, THE STATE
IS RESPONSIBLE FOR HIS RENT. HIS HIS
CARS ARE FUEL. YOU YOU HE DOESN'T EVEN
KNOW THE PRICE OF FUEL BECAUSE IF HE WAS
TO POSITION HIMSELF AS AN ORDINARY MAN
HE WILL BE ORDINARY BUT HE'S HE SOUGHT
POWER
HE SOUGHT POWER AND THAT POWER COMES
WITH PRIVILEGES SO WE HAVE A GENERATION
OF MEN SEEKING WHAT POWER CAN NEVER
DELIVER BUT THE MOMENT THEY GET POWER
FOLLOWS THESE things
seeking first the kingdom the power THE
AUTHORITY THEY A SEAL OF HEAVEN. IT'S
NOT OF EARTH AND THE AND THE
RIGHTEOUSNESS, THE STANDARDS, NOT THE
GOAL, THE STANDARD. IT'S A LANGUAGE of
daily walk of heaven. And these things,
God calls them things.
When you are a son, God does not call
them blessings. When you are a son, he
calls them things. When you are a child,
he calls them blessings. IT DEPENDS.
GRAMMAR SHIFTS with ranks.
HOW GOD TALKS TO A son is different from
how he talks to a child. A child should
be preserved not to be offended
because that child can cause tantrums
and say Lord is either you come down or
I come up today. You you see those songs
of MY MIRACLE IS TODAY. THOSE ARE
children prayers.
A child wants it now. But a son can stay
in the wilderness until the day of his
manifesting.
>> And you see the reason why the church is
not as powerful is because an army of
children cannot take a territory.
It takes hands to be entrusted with a
territory.
Please go to Matthew, I think Matthew 3
in the baptism
because there was silence for 400 years.
Israel was anticipating for the voice of
God. They were waiting. You study
history, they will tell YOU MANY MEN
CAME AND they thought they were the one.
But they realized this was not the one.
They were waiting for the voice of God.
And suddenly a voice came from heaven
saying this is my beloved son in whom I
am well pleased. This is what was that?
AFTER MALACHI, GOD NEVER SENT A PROPHET.
God endorsed his son. It was heaven that
thundered again. GOD HIMSELF spoke and
he said this.
There was no audience. There was no
crowd. But creation had that voice.
That's why when the sun stood the sea
could obey. That's why when the sun
stood, DISEASES WILL BOW. THAT voice
thundered in eternity. CREATION HEARD.
THE SON HAS COME. SO THERE is one we
must watch for. The only person in that
river was John.
It was John. But heaven affirmed and
said this. It was also to tell you John
was not the voice.
Look at 18. Is 18 there. Continue. If
there's another verse there.
Then Jesus was led by the spirit into
the wilderness to be tempted by the
devil. After that endorsement, the first
thing you had to meet the one that
checks men
and do you know what was the question
there? If you're the son of God, the
greatest attack of a believer is
identity. The first attack of Adam is do
you know that if you eat you will be
like God. It was not a language of
fruit. It was a language of identity. If
I tell you you are not a man, will you
walk naked to prove to men you are a
man? You know that you know you're a
man. So it is conflict of identity that
made them eat the fruit.
Somebody say the man Jesus.
>> Somebody say the man Jesus.
>> So we need the revelation of the man
Jesus. Hallelujah.
The man Jesus slept.
The God Jesus stopped the winds. The man
Jesus
when you look at him wept in the tomb of
Lazarus. The God Jesus raised Lazarus.
>> The man Jesus was hungry. But the God
Jesus fed 9,000. First Lord 5,000.
Second cohort 4,000.
There were two cohorts of feeding.
>> Yes sir.
>> Yes. And those were men. And children
are always many in a meeting and women.
So you can see the number. And someone
said, "We missed the miracle of not
seeing how many were fed. We missed the
miracle of how did Jesus preach to
10,000 without a without a microphone.
We see the breads that was after they
were they had the word for a whole day.
So they had a seminar. They had doctor
conference. Whole day, no sound, no
microphone. But he preached to more than
10,000 without a microphone. So that's
another miracle.
So the first revelation is the
revelation of the virgin.
The second one is the man Jesus. Number
three, the suffering messiah. We need
the revelation of the suffering. The
suffering messiah. He was bruised for
our infirmities, iniquities. when you
read that in Isaiah I think is 54 55
very graphical you can look for that
scripture very graphical we need to
understand the suffering of Jesus and I
can tell you uh pastor Kjagua when we
teach these things without systematic
order we confuse the audience we should
move from the virgin birth come to the
man Jesus come to the suffering messiah
the Bible says just as many were
astonished as you so his visage was mad
more than any man and his form more than
the sons of men. There was nothing good
to behold on the mountains of Calvary.
He was bruised. He was wounded. We need
the revelation of the suffering Messiah.
It tells us what he did so that we can
understand what we received.
The revelation of the suffering. Now the
problem is the devil. But he was wounded
for our transgression. He was bruised
for our iniquities. Isaiah 53:5. The
chastisement for our peace was upon him
and by his stripes we are healed. We
need to understand the reality of the
suffering Messiah. It's very important.
But the victory of a believer is not in
the reality of his suffering only. The
the suffering of the Messiah is the
beginning of our victory.
YOU KNOW OUR EVANGELISM stopped at
crucification.
It stops there. And that gospel even the
DEVIL CAN FINANCE IT. WHY? It is a
victim gospel.
And that's why WHEN YOU ALL YOU teach is
the cross crucifixion of Christ, you
will have men that want to help Jesus
because in their memory he's dead. And
I've kept on saying on this altar
sometimes I don't like those
dramatization of a baby Jesus and a
dying Jesus.
You can imagine what we are planting in
those children.
Baby Jesus Christmas then Easter we
focus on the suffering and on the death
that child will perpetually see that
savior as a victim.
You can imagine a movie that ends with a
man on a cross and then you say that man
is a hero.
Now if you if if you are for real you'll
begin to look for the hero in that man.
Can I tell you the truth? The next two
revelations is where the victory of the
church is. The revelation of the
resurrection of Christ. Number four, the
resurrection of the Messiah. The
resurrection of Christ. And number five,
the glorification of Christ. The
glorification
THE THE SUFFERING OF CHRIST is the lamp
dimension.
The glorification of Christ is the king
dimension and the Lord dimension.
These five revelations are very
important. Number one is the virgin
path. Number two is the
talk to me. Number two is the
>> man Jesus. Number three,
>> that is the lamb dimension. And number
four,
>> the resurrected
Christ or Messiah. This is the level of
where now he has conquered death.
NOW THIS THE CONCEPT OF THE resurrected
Messiah is where we have Colossians.
That's where we HAVE COLOSSIANS WHERE HE
publicly disarmed.
He publicly disarmed.
Go to Colossians 2:5.
Colossians 2:15.
He publicly disarmed. Colossians 2:15.
Everybody read.
Having
>> disarmed
principalities,
>> powers,
>> HE MADE A PUBLIC SPECTACLE OF THEM,
TRIUMPHING OVER THEM. Now look at this.
The reality of this happened on the
cross. It happened on the cross. Look at
this in NLT. I think we saw it better in
NLT.
I'll show you something that is
connected NLT.
In this way, he disarmed the spiritual
rulers and authorities. He shamed them
publicly by his victory over them on the
cross. Look at it on message Bible. Let
me have a few people. Let me show you
what this thing used to happen. This
disarming.
HE STRIP OFF SPIRITUAL TYRANTS in the
universe of the asham authority at the
cross and mar them naked through the
streets. I want to show you what used to
happen in those olden days
when they come and capture soldiers.
Yesterday I saw something in Kikuyo
where some people cornered a goon
and he had a real mio
a real weapon and they took the weapon
from him. That's is to disarm.
Are we together? You know there's a man
of God who said there was a man who used
to be deep in their school. And this man
was preaching and he said and Jesus
disarmed the devil
and they said amen. So
so later when later when he read the
scripture discovered it had nothing to
do with removing hands and legs. But
they they used to believe this man
cannot miss scripture. He must be the
deep one. So So I saw those man, they
cornered the man. He was strong. He even
had a jersey, military jersey. AND AND
AND THEY CORNERED HIM. THEN THEY TOOK
OUT THE WEAPONS. AND GUESS WHAT? PEOPLE
WERE FOLLOWING THE MAN,
you know, they were following him. They
telling him, "We don't like violence
here." And they kicked him out. Now in
the olden culture when men went to
battle
AND THEY MET AN OPPOSITION WHAT THE
PEOPLE will do they needed surviving
warriors
AS A SPECTACLE OF VICTORY. SO THEY NEVER
DESTROYED EVERYBODY IN THE BATTLE. YOU
you you you saw the rescue of the
American guy. Yes. From Iran.
>> Do you watch news?
An American airplane was shot and a and
a man and a man and a man was and and
two of THEIR PILOTS WERE INSIDE THE
territory of the enemy and the Iranians
announced on national TV if anyone gets
the people we'll give them £65,000
or £50,000 I think and it was on news.
So what they were doing is they wanted
to get that man alive so that it can be
a spectacle that we have the enemy we
have disarmed and we can do anything. I
want to believe if they've gotten those
American men they will be slapping them
live on TV and say p you Americans
because they want to show the Americans
we have now your men and we have
disarmed them and THEY CAN DO NOTHING
they are under our rulership. I was told
that operation costed them around 500
million to rescue two people. You know I
I looked at it from a corporate and a
ministry and even I said in the men
conference. Now you understand when we
mean leave no man behind is a military
language THAT WE CAN STAND 500 million
because of two souls.
Oh my god. Helicopters were taken.
military strategy, things that I've
NEVER SEEN FOR TWO MEN. And then I saw
the endurance of a man who stayed for 48
hours ON A CLIFF HOLDING onto hope and
life because these men are trained for
endurance.
The enemy is around but you're able to
do them. But I looked at it and I said,
"Can your company spend 500 million to
rescue you?" You know, I BEGAN TO ASK
MYSELF VERY HARD QUESTIONS. WHERE YOU
ARE WORKING, THE THE ORGANIZATION
YOU KNOW, I USED to work in the media
and the cameras were very expensive.
If you're working in the media, when you
get an accident, the director will call
AND ASK, "HI, IS THE CAMERA OKAY?"
"YES." AND THE GUY, "OKAY, SAH, let them
come." Because the camera was more
important than the guy. Now, this is
what they USED TO DO. ONCE THEY HAVE
CAPTURED THE ENEMY, they will disarm
them and then chain their hands
and chain their foot. And then the
commander of battle and and sometimes
they will put chains on their necks and
have a chain that they are pulling them.
Now follow me. And they will walk in the
streets of Limuru showing them the men
that had begun war. And these men were
naked. It was a language of humiliation.
THESE WERE THE STRONG MEN TRYING TO
TERRORIZE THE TERRITORY. NOW THEY ARE
PARADED AND PEOPLE WILL COME BECAUSE FOR
LONG NOBODY WILL DO BUSINESS BECAUSE
THERE was war, THERE WAS TERROR. AND SO
THE MOTHERS AND THE YOUNG PEOPLE WILL
COME AND THEY WILL begin to
Thank you. So, so this is exactly what
used to happen. Please get this. So, the
they will now pull them in the streets
and they will it was called a match of
victory but a match of shame. And so,
the people in THE CAMP HAVE EVIDENCE
THAT WE HAVE WON and we have slaves of
war. And everyone in the camp will begin
to clap celebrating for their VICTORY
AND KNOWING THAT THE ENEMY HAS BEEN
DEFEATED. AND MOST OF THE TIMES THE
PEOPLE THAT WERE paraded were the
commanders.
Not just THE JUNIOR, THEY TARGETED THE
ONES THAT WERE IN FRONT OF THE battle
because in every battle it is kings AND
COMMANDERS THAT DIED last because they
were not on the front line. They used to
be at THE BACK LINE. SO BY THE TIME YOU
REACH THE KING and the commander IT
AUTOMATICALLY TELLS YOU AT THAT LEVEL NO
MAN IS LEFT STANDING AND THIS ONE WILL
BE spared as spoils of war. Now they
have taken their weapons and the men can
do nothing.
Now let me bring it to scripture so that
you understand what God is trying to
say. So we have one enemy but this enemy
has also fashioned his cohorts with
power. The only thing that the devil
had, the only thing was death.
That was the only power that was left in
his custody.
SO WHEN MAN FELL, HE GOT ACCESS to some
things. And one power that the devil had
was death. That was the thing. NOW, IN
ALL THIS CALVARY DRAMA,
THE DEVIL HAS TO BE SURE HE'S UNLEASHING
his final arrow on the last target
because he's like a bee.
If you've ever kept bees,
a bee has only one sting.
A bee cannot sting two people.
So if a bee comes and stings shady here
and we see there is a swelling and we
know it's only one bee, we can even play
with it
>> because IT HAS THE SOUND OF A BEE,
>> THE NOISE OF A BEE,
>> BUT IT DOES NOT HAVE THE STING OF A BEE.
AH, so it means it is a useless bee S
>> BECAUSE WHATEVER MAKES YOU RUN AWAY FROM
THE BEE IS THE STING. SO NOW THE STING
IS NOT THERE. SO THAT BEE IS STILL A
BEE. BUT AT the end OF THE DAY, IT
DOESN'T HAVE THE POWER THAT MADE IT A
BEE THAT we afraid of. SO THE ENEMY HAS
ONLY ONE WEAPON AT HIS CUSTODY. HE ONLY
HAS ONE THING LEFT FOR HIM. HE CANNOT
WASTE IT. HE ONLY HAS ONE STING, ONE
BULLET. HE CANNOT WASTE IT. In his
foolishness, he begins to look for ONE
MAN.
WHAT HE DOES NOT KNOW IS THAT ALSO THE
MAN CAME FOR THAT THING THAT HE HAS
>> BECAUSE IF I DO NOT DISARM HIM THEN MY
CHILDREN AND MY SONS WILL BE IN TROUBLE.
SO I MUST COME AND TAKE HOLD OF THE
ENEMY. SO WHAT JESUS ACTUALLY CAME AND
DID HE POSITIONED HIMSELF ON CALVARY
LIKE A BULL'S EYE TELLING THE DEVIL
BRING IT ON ON ME. UH BRING IT ON ON ME
BECAUSE WHAT YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND YOU
HAVE THE STING OF DEATH I HAVE THE POWER
OF RESURRECTION SO I HAVE WHAT DEALS
WITH DEATH I I DON'T KNOW IF YOU YOU SEE
MEN THAT KEEP SNAKES THEY HAVE ANOTHER
POISON STRONGER THAN THE POISON OF THE
THE VENOM SO THEY HAVE ANOTHER VENOM SO
THAT BY THE TIME YOU ARE BEATEN BY A
COBRA YOU TAKE ANOTHER INJECTION OF A
COBRA WHICH IS MORE POWERFUL THAN THE
VENOM THEN WHAT HAPPENS IS THE SECOND
VENOM NEUTRALIZES THE POWER OF THE
PREVIOUS VENOM. THE RESURRECTION POWER
IS MORE POWERFUL THAN DEATH.
>> SO HIM THAT WAS HANGING ON THAT CROSS
KNEW WHAT HE WAS HIDING IN HIS ARMORY.
THE DEVIL DID NOT UNDERSTAND ABOUT THE
MYSTERY OF THE RESURRECTION. HE THOUGHT
IT'S ANOTHER DAY OF DOING WHAT HE DID TO
THE FIRST ADAM. WHAT HE DIDN'T
UNDERSTAND, THE FIRST ADAM WAS A LIVING
SPIRIT. THE SECOND ADAM IS A LIFEGIVING
SPIRIT. THERE IS A DIFFERENCE. YOU
CANNOT DESTROY HIM. YOU CAN ATTACK THE
BODY, BUT YOU CANNOT DESTROY HIM. AND
THAT'S WHY WHEN JESUS STOOD ON THE
CROSS, THE ONLY WEAPON THE DEVIL HAD WAS
LAUNCHED ON HIM. AND JESUS RECEIVED IT
PROUDLY. AND BY THE TIME HE RECEIVED IT,
THAT IS WHEN NOW HE SAID, "IT IS
FINISHED. THE BATTLE IS OVER. THE ONE
THAT TERRORIZED THE CHURCH HAS JUST
RELEASED HIS FINAL BULLET. HE IS
POWERLESS. HE HAS NO ABILITY. NOW THE
CHURCH CAN ARISE WITH THE GOSPEL.
BECAUSE WHAT IS THE GOSPEL? IT IS THE
GOOD NEWS OF WHAT JESUS HAS ALREADY DONE
IN CALVARY. WHAT WAS THE GOSPEL IN THE
OLDEN DAYS? THERE WAS A MAN IN BATTLE
WHO WAS STAYING THERE AS A MESSENGER
WAITING A COMMAND FROM THE COMMANDER TO
BE TOLD GO AND TELL THE PEOPLE THAT WE
HAVE FINISHED THE BATTLE. LET THE PEOPLE
BEGIN TO CELEBRATE BECAUSE WE HAVE WON
THE BATTLE. THE WORK OF THAT MAN WAS TO
CARRY THE GOOD NEWS BACK INTO THE
VILLAGE AND TELL THEM LISTEN THE ENEMY
HAS BEEN WON. YOU DON'T NEED TO WORRY
ANYMORE. CONTINUE PLANTING. LET YOUR
CHILDREN GO TO SCHOOL, DO BUSINESS AS
YOU ARE SUPPOSED TO BE. IN THAT BATTLE
OF CALVARY, AS JESUS WAS THERE, HE
LOOKED ON THE OPERATION OF THE ENEMY.
THE DEVIL DID. THE BIBLE SAYS, "IF THE
DEVIL KNEW, HE WOULD NOT HAVE ENTERED
ROME TO CRUCIFY JESUS." HE TOOK THE
FINAL SHOT. WHEN IT WAS ON HIM, HE SAID,
"TELESSST DIE. THE BATTLE HAS BEEN WON."
AND GUESS WHAT? HE CONVERTED YOU AND ME
TO BE THE CARRIERS OF THE GOOD NEWS. WE
ARE THE ONES NOW COMING FROM THE
BATTLEFIELD. WE ARE NOT IN THE
BATTLEFIELD. WE ARE COMING FROM THE
BATTLEFIELD WITH THE GOOD NEWS THAT THE
battle
I WISH I HAVE A CHILD THIS MORNING
BECAUSE IT IS NOT ABOUT WHAT YOU ARE
SEEING. IT IS ABOUT WHAT YOU KNOW. I
WISH YOU CAN HEAR THOSE OLD MOTHERS. YOU
KNOW YESTERDAY I WAS THERE WITH MY
GRANDMOTHER. SHE SAID SOMETHING THAT I
WILL NEVER FORGET. She said,
"THERE IS A GENERATION THAT DOES NOT
KNOW THAT YOU CAN ACTUALLY SPEAK TO THE
DEVIL AND TELL THE DEVIL, LEAVE MY
FAMILY, LEAVE MY CAREER, LEAVE MY
BUSINESS, LEAVE MY HEALTH, LEAVE MY LIFE
BECAUSE I RECEIVE THE GOOD NEWS." YOU
ARE DEFEATED.
THE GOOD NEWS IS NOT MATTHEW, MARK, JOHN
AND LUKE.
>> YES,
>> THAT IS WHAT YOU ARE TAUGHT IN CR. THAT
IS NOT THE REALITY. THE GOOD NEWS IS THE
TOTALITY OF THE BIBLE. IT IS THE NEWS
THAT WITCHES HAVE NO POWER. THE POWER OF
CALVARY IS ABOUT THE POWER OF
PRINCIPALITIES, THE POWERS OF RULERS.
WITCHES HAVE NO AUTHORITY. DIVERS HAVE
NO AUTHORITY. YOU MAY LOOK AT ME AND
TELL ME, "PASTOR, DO YOU KNOW THERE WAS
SOMETHING THEY DID? THEY BROKE CALABASH.
BEFORE THEY BROKE THAT CALABASH,
SOMETHING HAPPENED BEFORE THEY DID
WHATEVER THEY DID. WE COME FROM A
KINGDOM OF GOOD NEWS.
>> SO NOW ON CALVARY,
>> TELL YOUR NEIGHBOR, CARRY GOOD NEWS.
>> AND GOOD NEWS HAS GOOD and news.
>> IT HAS DEEDS. IT IS NOT JUST NEWS.
>> THAT'S WHY TESTIMONIES MUST BE UPON YOUR
MOUTH. H IF YOU DON'T HAVE A TESTIMONY,
I'LL BE SURPRISED FOR ME. THAT'S WHY I
DON'T GIVE PEOPLE HERE A CHANCE TO COME
AND TESTIFY BECAUSE IT'S SUPPOSED TO BE
NORMAL. IN FACT, WE NEED A A A SPACE
WHERE WHY ARE YOU NOT TESTIFYING?
WHY ARE YOU NOT TESTIFYING YET YOU HAVE
THE SON? WE WE DON'T NEED TWO PEOPLE
HERE TO COME AND TELL US OR YOU KNOW
DURING THE WEEK AND SOME OF THEM ARE NOT
TESTIMONIES. THERE ARE SITUATIONS
TOKENS.
THOSE ARE NOT TESTIMONIES. A TESTIMONY
IS WHAT ONLY GOD CAN DO. HALLELUJAH. A
TESTIMONY IS WHEN YOU WAKE UP AND SAY,
"I AM BORN AGAIN. I AM REDEEMED OF THE
FATHER. I AM SANCTIFIED. I AM WASHED. I
HAVE CONFIDENCE THAT WHEN THE TRUMPET
SOUND, WHEN THE RIGHTEOUS ONE COMES FOR
THE SON, I'LL BE AMONG THE NUMBER. THAT
IS THE TESTIMONY.
GO AND LOOK FOR THOSE OLD WOMEN, THOSE
OLD PASTORS. THEY WILL TELL YOU
TODAY WE HAVE A LOT OF RUBBISH ON THE
ALTAR.
IS NO LONGER ABOUT ETERNAL LIFE. PEOPLE
ARE DRIVING THEIR CARS TO HELL. PEOPLE
ARE BUILDING MANSIONS AND THEY ARE DYING
THERE. IT IS PEOPLE ARE BUILDING
MANSIONS THEY CANNOT SLEEP IN. AND
PLEASE NEVER GET ME WRONG.
NIKON.
Those were the testimonies. Look for
those men. I met a woman in my village.
Her husband has been bedridden for 20
years. She takes care of her. And I was
there going to conffort her and she said
many of the afflictions of the Russians
but God shall that woman preached to me
as I was looking at a DYING HUSBAND. I
SAID WHAT HAPPENED TO THE FAITH OF THE
GENERALS? Then I discovered we are
teaching Sunday school lectures in main
church. SO WE HAVE CHILDREN IN CHURCH
WHO CANNOT ENDURE AFFLICTION. WHERE ARE
THE PS OF OUR DAY? WHO CAN WRITE, "I
HAVE RUN THE RACE. I HAVE KEPT THE FAITH
AND NOW I'M READY TO BE POWERED AS A
LIVING SACRIFICE." WHERE ARE THE JONES
OF OUR DAY? WHO CAN SAY THAT I'M IN
PATMOS? I AM IN PATMOS. PATMOS IS A JAIL
BECAUSE OF THE GOSPEL AND THE MESSAGE OF
CHRIST.
One firing and we have a sympathy
meeting.
And please don't get me wrong, IF WE
HAVE TO TRAIN YOU, THERE ARE THINGS YOU
MUST MUST OUTGROW.
>> CUZ THE DEVIL HAS KEPT US BUSY WITH
USELESS THINGS. RENT, school fees. Those
are the things that are KEEPING US BUSY.
OUR JOBS HAVE BECOME OUR IDOLS. THERE IS
A LEVEL YOU LOOK AT THAT JOB AND KNOW
IT'S NOT NO man gave me this job. I AM
HERE BY DIVINE APPOINTMENT AND THE DAY
MY ASSIGNMENT WILL END AND LEAVE. AND
THAT DOES NOT MEAN YOU GIVE A MEDIOCRE
SERVICE. YOU ARE THE BEST IN YOUR PLACE.
BUT YOU KNOW YOU ARE NOT THAT THE
MERCIES OVER HR. YOU KNOW YOU CAN HIRE
AND FIRE
>> SO THAT NOW YOU ARE NOT MANIPULATED.
THERE IS AN AUTHORITY WE CARRY IN JESUS.
I SAY THERE IS AN AUTHORITY WE CARRY. HE
MADE A PUBLIC SPECTACLE ON CALVARY. IT
WAS A DISARMING BY THE TIME
ALLAH
PRESERVE BECAUSE THE ONLY THING I CAN DO
IS NOW ROLL LIKE A ROARING LION LIKE
LIKE LIKE HE'S NOT THE ONE THERE IS THE
REAL LION OF JUDAH
WHEN HE ROLLS
A MAN SENT ME A DOCUMENTARY IT WAS
called Mr. T the Lions of South Africa.
I watched it
>> because it had my name. Go and look for
Mr. T the lion of South Africa. IT WAS A
PACK OF FIVE LIONS.
>> IN THE TERRITORY of lions, Kjagua. WHEN
WHEN A LION delivers and the cubs are
male, there is problem.
Yeah. When when the when the father lion
raises the cubs, there is an age it
reaches, the father kicks them out
because two lions cannot roll in the
same territory.
THAT'S WHY BACK IN THE DAYS,
it is called the exit.
And it IS ILLEGAL WHEN YOUR FATHER IS IN
THE HOUSE ASKING FOR FOOD.
BY THE TIME YOU'RE 25,
SIMBA THAT THERE IS AN AGE YOU REACH AND
YOU DON'T YOU DON'T CHASE THEM
CEREMONIOUSLY. YOU KICK THEM OUT TO GO
AND FIND THEIR TERRITORY. SO WHAT DOES
THE FATHER LION DO? IT WAKES UPS IN THE
MORNING AND SAY WHO? SO IF THE CHILDREN
HEAR THE SOUND OF THEIR FATHER, THEY GO
FURTHER
BECAUSE THEY KNOW THEY ARE STILL IN THE
TERRITORY OF THEIR FATHER UNTIL WHERE
THEY CANNOT SEE THEY HEAR THE SOUND OF
THEIR FATHER. SO THOSE FIVE LIONS are
led by a a lion called Mr.
AND THEY TERRORIZED THE SAVYLVANAS OF
SOUTH Africa because territories are not
given THEY ARE TAKEN. THEY FOUND THEY
FOUND OTHER ANIMALS IN THE TERRITORY but
they began TO FIGHT THAT MR. T DIED
FIGHTING. I said I think that's the
spirit I have. The territory must know
we are here. Amen.
>> And that's WHAT WE DO SPIRITUALLY WHEN
WE BEGIN TO PRAY IS A ROLE IN THE
SPIRIT. SO THAT AS FAR AS OUR VOICE
GOES, DEMONS NEED TO KNOW THEY IN THE
WRONG TERRITORY. SO THERE IS A TIME YOU
ROLL TO MARK YOUR TERRITORY. THERE IS A
TIME YOU ROLL AS A SIGN OF PRIDE BECAUSE
WE BOAST IN CHRIST JESUS. IS SOMEONE
GETTING ME? LET ME TELL YOU, THE DEVIL
HAS NOTHING. THERE IS A REVELATION YOU
get
>> and I confirm this revelation because
there's a time doing deliverance and
THERE WAS A STUBBORN spirit until I
began to question my anointing. Then
there ARE CERTAIN DEMONS THAT LIVE NOT
BY SHOUTING but by revelation. So we
began to tell that spirit, listen, you
lost more than 2,000 years ago. You have
no power. Then the spirit said,
listen, this is the temple of the Holy
Spirit. Then other spirits gathered and
they said to talk to talk to. So we knew
now we were not dealing with one spirit.
BUT THE MOMENT THE SPIRIT SAYS TO END
THE wii we had told the spirit 2,000
years ago YOU LOST THE BATTLE. THEY know
>> that's why you need TO KNOW SCRIPTURE.
THERE'S AND WE WE PREACHED TO THAT
SPIRIT and it left. No war, no nothing
revelation because we are preaching from
a place of conviction.
When is the last day you address the
devil from authority, not fear?
Tell your neighbor from today
because it IS WAR AND BY REVELATION. SO
GUESS WHAT HAPPENED? THIS IS WHAT
HAPPENED. He publicly Jesus was now
saying when he died on the cross
everything that the devil had
and the devil hates these preachings
may operate in a false perception
but the moment men begin to know the
truth there's something we used to sing
when we are learning tongue twisting
kora kora
That's how we behave. You know, you know
those who are coming from Kenya.
Do you know what that means? There is a
there is a kana kana is child of kicora
and that child sees a frog.
So the child runs and the frog RUNS CUZ
THE FROG knows who the CHILD IS BUT THE
CHILD DOES NOT KNOW WHO he is or he is.
So the child is running from what is
running from her or him. That is how
believers are. The devil sees you and
run and you you are running from the
devil. DO YOU KNOW JOHN HAD A REVELATION
and it SAYS FROM THE DAYS of John the
Baptist the KINGDOM OF HEAVEN SUFFEREES
VIOLENT THE INTERPRETATION THERE
ADVANCES VIOLENTLY. SO WHEN WE SEE KORA
KORA WE DON'T RUN AWAY WE RUN TOWARDS
CHASING THE KORA BECAUSE WE ARE THE SONS
OF GOD AND WE ARE NO LONGER ON THE
DEFENSIVE WE ARE NOW ON THE OFFENSIVE.
THAT'S WHY IN THE ARMOR OF GOD, YOU
DON'T COVER YOUR BACK
>> BECAUSE WE ARE NOT GIVING THE DEVIL THE
BACK. WE ARE MOVING FROM ONE TERRITORY
TO ANOTHER. IT IS A LANGUAGE OF I AM
COVERED AT THE FRONT BECAUSE THERE IS NO
ONE DAY I WILL EVER TURN BACK. IN FACT,
I AM NOT FIGHTING FOR VICTORY. I AM
FIGHTING FROM VICTORY. WHAT I AM DOING,
I AM IMPLEMENTING
THE VICTORY. THAT'S WHY WE PRAY IN THE
NAME Jesus
>> publicly disarmed.
>> SO IN CALVARY,
JESUS received the final arrow.
The devil, principalities, authorities,
all of them lost their rank. When it
comes to a child of destiny, your case
is different.
deliverance.
Uh
TV
Oh, there's a man who saw his wife on
TV.
than conquerors.
>> More than conquerors
>> and it is not a story.
>> It is a reality. We are the carriers of
the good news. We speak the good news
until it becomes our reality.
>> We speak it. Do do you know some aunties
who have been praying for you from the
time you are young and up to date they
still pray for you. You found them
saved. They are still saved and they
have never given up on salvation. Those
are the people we are raising that in
your home even if it's in the midst of
witches they will know there is one who
has another altar we CANNOT TOUCH YOUR
COUSINS WILL KNOW THERE IS ONE THERE IS
ONE we know THERE IS ONE WHO LOVES JESUS
AND YOU DON'T JUDGE THEM NO YOU SHARE
THE LOVE BUT THEY KNOW GENUINELY THIS
ONE IS A MAN OF FAITH
>> BECAUSE YOU HAVE THE GOOD AND YOU HAVE
the newsy
family gathering. They can see the good.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Before you even say the news,
>> sir,
>> they can see the good. How your marriage
is working, how your children are
growing,
>> even physically, how you are good. They
can sense the the glory of God upon your
life. See
It is error.
Where is the good in your news?
Lift up your hands and say from TODAY I
SHALL CARRY THE GOOD
>> AND CARRY THE NEWS. VICTORY IS MY
PORTION
>> IN THE NAME OF JESUS.
>> Now let me show you the correlation of
the two scriptures.
Have your seats briefly then I'll call
you. Are you learning something?
>> So he was PUBLICLY DISARMED. SO THEY
COME AND TELL us
that Jesus never considered himself to
be equal with God.
He never considered himself to be equal
with God though he was God. What does
that scripture mean? That when Jesus
took the form of a man, every privilege
in the godhood was abandoned.
He 100% became a man. Walked in the
limitations of the flesh. Walked in the
realities of the flesh. THOUGH HE STILL
COULD ACCESS his God dimension,
it was not far from him. And then they
come and tell us there are many things
you can say about that. abandoning the
pride, the privilege uh and all those
things to become to become man a and and
even you know walk in these limitations
of the flesh. He was no longer
omnipresent. He could only be at the
same place at the same time. He
abandoned that privilege of being
omnipresent. He abandoned the privileges
of the authorities and the powers that
he had in power in heaven that he will
show up in a meeting only demons could
sense his authority but ordinary people
don't even know that God is in town. You
can imagine how they were mishandling
him. A man he goes to visit a man and
the man says this man if only he knew
who this woman is. The people that
crucified him some were spitting on him
his whole creation he would have gotten
mad. And the Bible calls it obedience,
but the Bible also calls it humility.
Because the real definition of humility
is not softness.
They are soft, proud men.
In fact, you can be soft and short
>> and proud. I don't know why also people
think being short is a sign OF HUMILITY.
NO, IT'S HEIGHT.
YOU CAN HAVE A SHORT SOPRANO MAN PROUD.
A TALL MAN WITH BASE BUT HUMBLE. SO IT'S
NOT ABOUT THE SIZE OF YOUR BODY. IT'S
ABOUT THE CONTAINING of power. Humility
is power contained. That's humility. Is
power contained?
Some of you small promotion and you
terrorize everyone.
Sometimes even God looks at us.
Do you know the more you rise in God,
the more you lose yourself?
Some some of the most powerful preachers
I know, they are so humble and they
don't even know they are humble cuz
there are certain things in God that
demand blessings
before blessings.
People look at you and they wonder how
did you make it here and they think is
your ability and you look at them and
give them that cliche answer God and
they're like but you know that you know
this is not my saving this not my
ability it can only be God
and so power contained and this is
something you must learn because power
comes in many forms power comes in money
power comes politically power comes
socially you have a million followers
online right now you have sat at the
back but you're a manager. When you get
in the office, even the security salutes
you. Now the asher has harassed you,
given you a position you did not want.
That is humility.
Tell your neighbor, you look like a
candidate of humility.
Let me tell you what pride is.
A policeman has stopped you
traffic
and you work in some government office
and you begin to harass the man. Tell
him
that is pride.
That man is doing his work.
And you will be tested on matters pride.
And you can speak in tongues but very
proud. And I can tell you there are
certain things in God you can never do
if pride is your functionality. Let me
say this
there are certain battles in the flesh
that hinder move of power. We call them
uh power leakages like sexual
immorality. It leaks your power. So the
moment you master it, it means you can
operate at certain levels and frequency.
So there are certain things that leak
your power. Sexual immorality is one of
them. Gossip and slander is another one.
They they they leak your power. That
means um possibly in the realms of the
spirit you're supposed to command a
thousand, but you're commanding 10
because your authority and power is
leaking. And that's why now in that you
begin to walk in uh cleanseness. You can
still be in ministry but you're not
functioning at your full potential. The
problem with pride, it hinders your
elevation.
It is one thing to be a preacher that
you are meant to preach to 10,000 but
you're preaching to six. It's another
thing to be you are meant to be a
manager but you're still a secretary
because you have refused to be humble.
Are you getting me? SO THERE ARE CERTAIN
PROMOTIONS IN GOD THAT COME NOT BECAUSE
of prayer but because of the posture of
your heart.
One of the most humble people that even
heaven registers was Moses.
There is no man in the history of
scripture that was given the assignment
that Moses was given. Moses was a type
of a savior just like Jesus. But you can
see the currency of his elevation was
100% humility.
The second one that shows up in
scripture is Jesus. Many believers are
not in warfare. They are just proud.
And listen, you will be tested.
One of the things is the ability to
submit one to another.
Yes, you are the owner of that house,
but one day the Lord asks you to listen
to the house help. She has a point to
make and you tell her, "By the way,
you're making a lot of sense." I've
never seen it that way. But some of us
have a culture of dismissing anyone that
is lower than us. And it comes from our
culture. When you come from poverty,
I read something that says if you need
power, then you need to do something bad
because people who do good things, they
just need love.
And our interpretation of power in
Africa is oppression.
I I I was working with a friend of mine
from America and she asked me in this
land you can't introduce people without
do saying what they are doing. Can't we
just have genuine relationships cuz in
Kenya oh meet Liz Liz Liz is the senior
>> vocalist pastor life church
international muru this woman of God I
wish you you need to have a number. You
need to have a number. This one is a key
connector. Now the question is if if Liz
was a househel, does it mean she's not
worthy of that relationship?
Because our understanding of power in
Africa is achievements
>> and and that's why you know even in our
churches sometimes sorry to say this
sometimes when you give us these seats I
don't know what you mean.
When pastor T is sitting on this black
chair, what does it mean on the one
who's sitting on the purple chair? What
does is it a power equation or is it
comfort?
No, I'm I'm
but you see h someone might think when
they sit closer to me they are more
powerful
and it is possible to have a rebel next
to you Judas. Yet the real son is at the
back doing ushering work.
>> Am I speaking to anyone?
>> So, so humility is power
contained
and humility is a key in the spirit
because it is the elevator and the lever
of elevation.
Men that God lift must be humble enough
to be lifted. And there are two levels.
You can humble yourself or God can
humble you. The humbling of God is not
good. Ask Nebuchadnezzar.
as a king.
BY THE TIME HE LEFT THAT AREA, THE MAN
confessed that actually there is no
other god. They believe Nebuchadnezzar
got born again. So when the Bible says
humble yourselves and let me tell you
for those who are married, uh if you
have a loving wife, she'll never lie to
you.
If there's one person who can tell me
when I'm proud is my wife
otherwise you you cannot.
You can even praise me in my pride. And
that's the problem of surrounding
yourself with people that you are
perpetually raising. You need men that
can look straight on the eye and say,
know sometimes we preach and we give
stories
but your story
and is only your wife sometimes p and it
is not comfortable and I I said in the
gathering you need a wife who can
circumcise you like zippora
Sometimes I read the Bible.
You know, sometimes you have to to to to
look at THE BIBLE LITERALLY, BUT YOU ASK
YOURSELF, MOSES ACTUALLY cooperated
and Moses got circumcised. THEN
we'll deal with that matter next Sunday
when we have the teenagers because I'll
be teaching on why where the two sons of
Moses went.
Because when Moses chased his wife,
those children never saw the power the
father walked in.
And the children of Aaron inherited the
mantle. The sons of Moses. We don't hear
about them. But one of the grandson is
located later in scripture as a le for
worship.
One day you remember those moments. You
didn't know what was happening. But you
saw mommy on the knees. You will
understand. She was praying. That's why
we keep Sunday school.
But they must see you kneel. They must
see tears come from your eyes worshiping
the living God. That is more powerful
than Sunday school. Those the day she
will begin to pray, she will say, "I saw
my mom kneel." She will kneel.
nor is it shaken.
Let let me let me go to the scripture.
>> Tell your neighbor, neighbor,
>> Jesus humbled himself.
>> Oh my God. Let me share this. The
precursor of this scripture is that he
humbled himself and became a bond
servant.
He became a bond servant. He became a
bond servant. That word is the precursor
of any other operation that happened in
the time of Jesus.
There are
six things, five things about
a bondervant. And these five things can
actually lead to the definition of a
bone servant. A bondervant was one owned
by another. A bondervant was one owned
by another.
Number two,
a bondervant
did not have anything that belonged to
them. They didn't have anything that was
their own. So a bondervant was one owned
by another.
So you are another person's property.
They did not have anything that was
their own.
They they possessed nothing.
Born servants they lived to do the will
of their master. A bondervant lived to
do the will of their master. Now you
understand the cry of Jesus. Not my will
but your will. Because he was a bond
servant.
A bondervant
did not have privileges or rights.
He did not have any privileges or
rights. He lived for another.
A bondervant did not have privileges or
rights. He live for another. Number
five.
A bondervant surrendered voluntarily.
In Exodus 21:5 and 6, we see something
here
that no man was born as a bondervant,
but many serborn servants were slaves
that gave themselves up to their masters
willingly and perpetually.
No man was born as a born servant, but
these were ordinary slaves that gave
themselves to their masters willingly
and perpetually.
The Bible says uh in Exodus chapter
number 21:5 and 6. Exodus 215 and 6.
This is the law of a bond servant.
Exodus, the Bible says, "But if the
servant plainly say, I love my master,
my wife, and my children, I will not go
out free." Look at six. Then his master
shall bring him to the judges. He shall
also bring him to the door or to the
doorpost, and his master shall pierce
his ear with an all, and he shall serve
him forever. Please write this down.
There were six ways that a man became a
slave. There were six ways that a man
became a slave. Number one, you became a
slave through debt.
You became a slave through debt. And
debt was a product of poverty. So if I
owned you, I will tell you instead of me
because I cannot afford the money, let
me let me come and work for you for this
number of days and don't pay me. As I
work, get your wages from the days I am
going to work. Israel was more of an
agricultural economy. So people gave
their services for free and and and
instead of being paid the debt was
canceled. So the first thing was
poverty. We see this in 2 Kings chapter
number four where when the woman says
that the debtors are coming and they
taking my children as slaves. So people
actually gave themselves to slavery
because of debt. Number two, it was
because of criminal penalty.
Criminal penalty.
Criminal penalty. There was something
called financial restitution.
Financial restitution. So you have come
and you have stolen my cow.
And when returning the cow, there is a
pre fee you are supposed to return it
with. Because the days you stole the
cow, I made a loss of 10,000. So not
only are you supposed to return the cow,
but you're supposed to return also
10,000. So since you sometimes if you
don't have the 10,000, you work for me
as a slave for for the time needed for
me to recover my 10,000. So it was also
a criminal penalty which carried the
language of financial restitution.
Number three, it was also a place of um
uh economic desperation. Economic
desperation.
This is where people gave themselves
upper slaves so that they can get food
and other things. We see this from the
story of Ruth. Ruth surrendered as a
slave uh in the in the in the fiards of
Boas so that she can receive food. She
never went there for wages. She was
collecting and cleaning of what was
falling by the fence. So it was also
economic desperation.
Number four, you could also become a a
slave be because you are a prisoner of
war. Prisoner of war. When men were
caught in battle, the whole story of
Babylonians, when when the children of
Israel landed in Babylon, they became
slaves there. Prisoners of war were
actually made slaves. Prisoners of war.
And it was considered as part of the
wages of war that you have prisoners you
have captured. So you have free labor.
Number five, there was also inherited
slavery. Inherited slavery. And when you
look at these things, some of them bear
spiritual connotation. When you were
born as a child of a slave,
automatically you belong to the master
that owned the slave,
inherited slavery. When you were born as
a child of a slave, you you
automatically became
um a subject to the master that owned
your parents. So there was inherited or
born into slavery. Number six, there was
also slavery through kidnapping.
Sometimes people will be kidnapped and
they were taken as slaves sometimes on
the on on transport uh uh routes uh
cargo routes and all these things and so
they were taken as slaves. This was
illegal. But in all these levels of
slavery, WHEN A PERSON FOUND that the
master was good and the master treated
them fairly, a man will actually go
because the law dictated in every
seventh year that people ought to
release all the slaves and especially
the year of the jubilee. So a slave was
meant to work for you six years and then
you release them. You give them a
Sabbath on the seventh year. So some
people found masters that were very good
and what they will do in the day of
their release they will go and tell
their master you've been an amazing
master and now I give myself to you
permanently as a slave and those slaves
moved from becoming ordinary slaves and
they became bond slaves. Are we
together? They become now they became
now the bond servants. Meaning that they
gave their documents, their rights and
everything that they had, they gave it
out to the master
and they became the property of the
master. And when you made that decision,
judges were called. There is that thing
that makes holes in belts and they will
come and pin your ear on a door and
create a permanent hole so that when you
are walking in the streets anyone that
sees a man with a hole you know that's a
slave on of another person meaning that
you can you can't own them but they are
owned not temporarily but permanently
they are owned by someone different and
I think that's when people are fighting
the language of putting earrings because
the biblical language was a man pierced
his ear, but it was a hole in the ear as
a sign that this is a slave of another.
And back in the cultural days, people
that gave themselves as born servants
received certain privileges
with with the master because when YOU
HAVE A BORN servant and an ordinary
servant, one is like family to you. And
now when we come to the New Testament,
we see that the writers of the new were
using the tongue and the power and the
pattern of the old to identify
themselves as born servants. There are
seven people who call themselves bone
servant. In the Bible, number one was
Paul. Paul referred to himself as a
bondervant dos of Christ. Romans chapter
number one and verse one. And when you
look at the power and the assignment of
this men, it was not ordinary. Paul was
entrusted with the mission of the
gentile church. Meaning that there are
certain levels of entrustment,
assignment, authority that can only be
given when you become a bondervant. Paul
number two, Timothy, who was a son of
Paul. Philippians chapter number one and
verse one. Philippians chapter number
one and verse one. Timothy also calls
himself a bondervant. He identifies with
that title. And later we see he's the
man that was given the church in Ephesus
that had 100,000 members. Number three,
we have John, the writer of Revelation.
John was entrusted with the mysteries of
the apocalyptic or ecclesiastics.
John the only writer that wrote about
the end times. The Lord entrusted him
with the mysteries of the end. He also
called himself a bondervant. We see
every man that identified as a bone
servant there were certain levels of
entrustment that heaven gave them.
YOU'LL BE SURPRISED THAT MARY Luke
chapter number 1 and 38 Mary the mother
of Jesus when the angel came Mary said I
AM YOUR SERVANT. LET IT BE done to me as
the Lord wills as a servant of God. Luke
chapter number one and verse 38. When
Mary positioned herself as a bondervant,
ONE WITHOUT HER RIGHTS, ONE THAT IS AN
OWNER OF GOD, ONE THAT IS willing to do
the will of the master, she was
entrusted with the birthing of Jesus.
Favored and blessed are you among all
women. The secret of Mary was being a
bond servant. Number
number five, Jude the halfbrother of
Jesus became also a bondervant. Maybe he
learned from his brother. Six, James,
who was the elder of the church in uh
Jerusalem. You see this in Jude 1:1 and
James 1:1, James was a bone servant. And
number seven, Peter. James was the elder
of the church in Jerusalem. Peter also
became a bondervant. Uh in second Peter
chapter number one and verse one, all
these men identify as bone servant.
Remember a bondervant is one owned by
another. A bondervant has nothing of his
own. A bondervant lives to do the will
of the master. A bondervant is one that
has SURRENDERED LIFE, NO RIGHTS, NO
PRIVILEGES. A BONDERVANT is one that
voluntarily comes and volunteers to be a
bondervant. So when Jesus uses that word
that I
Jesus humbled himself AND BECAME A BOND
SERVANT
THAT WORD QUALIFIED HIM FOR ALL
authority that heaven could deliver
because it tells you he was owned by the
father. HE IT WAS TO TELL YOU THERE IS
NOTHING THAT HE HAD THAT WAS HIS OWN. I
do nothing other than that which I see
my father do. He had to live for the
will of the father. He lived as
surrendered. He surrendered the
privileges and the life and the rights
of becoming god. And the final one it
was voluntarily. He gave himself to be
used by the father. Allow me to tell you
church, there is a level of service
where God is not just looking for
servants. He's looking for bond
servants. IT IS ONE OF THE HARDEST
dimension but that's the dimension of
glory and power. THERE ARE CERTAIN
THINGS GOD cannot entrust a man who has
not entrusted himself to God fully.
THERE ARE CERTAIN DIMENSIONS OF
OPERATION, RESOURCES AND POWER THAT WE
CANNOT ENTER until we come to a place
whereby we live for only one God. And it
is out of this that now Jesus the Bible
comes and tells us not only did he the
form of the BOND SERVANT AND COMING IN
the likeness of man. Everybody read I
want to tie this with the other one then
we pray. Look at 8.
And being found in appearance as a man,
he humbled himself and became obedient
to the point of death, even the death of
the cross. We handled this I think last
Sunday. The death of the cross. It was
not just any other death. It was the
death of the cross. Shameful, torture.
So this was not just an ordinary thing.
Before we come to therefore, there are
things that act as a precursor. HE WAS A
BONDERVANT. HE ENDURED the death. HE
OBEYED AND HUMBLED HIMSELF. This is what
qualified him to bear a name that
everything on heaven, on earth, even
under the earth will bow. Now, let me do
a demonstration so that you can
understand what this scripture means.
REMEMBER, THERE IS A FIRST level whereby
we have disarmed the devil. Are we
together? Are you Are we together? So,
let me have my people again. the first
level.
Pastor Kevin, come. So, this is called a
walk of shame.
Let me have the worshippers because
you're in uniform. Come and partner with
you. Now, Pastor Kevin, now these are
your prisoners a command of battle.
So listen, this is what happened. Now
pull them, pull them, walk with them,
walk with them. That's how
they are defeated
and you need to clap because
the powers that terrorized you have now
lost. So the people
Kevin, you're not holding their hand
to me. Hallelujah. The victory has been
accorded.
Are you getting it? So now, meaning that
the enemy has been dealt with. Now the
second part, the Bible says now, now
come worshippers.
I I want you to stand in two rows. Two
rows.
Yes.
So yeah, there are two rows and give me
space. Give me space in the two rows.
Now Jeremy come
my brother the one that was leading
praise.
Separate in the row. Separate in the
row. At least
there were two people.
There were two people. The Bible here
says and being found in the appearance
he humbled himself and became obedient
to the point of death even death. Look
at N. Therefore, Godo also has highly
exalted him and given him the name which
is above every name. Now look at this.
That
10 that at the name of Jesus, the
mention of the name of Jesus, every knee
will bow. Do you know what that means?
When a king was coming in a territory in
the olden days, there was a man called a
herald.
So the king has not come. And this man
would run in the streets shouting Jesus.
Now shout Jesus.
>> Jesus.
>> Now
>> listen as the man is shouting Jesus.
Every knee will go down and bow and say
long live the king. Now let's do it.
Jesus has not yet appeared. IS AT THE
BIBLE SAYS AT THE MENTION
>> NOT AT THE APPEARANCE.
IT WAS AT THE MENTION
>> BECAUSE THE TERRITORY KNOWS WHO THE king
is.
>> SO THE MENTION OF THAT NAME, ANYTHING
THAT IS UNDER HIM MUST BOW.
>> NOW THE BIBLE GIVES ME A VERY GOOD
EXAMPLE. NOW GO TO HEAVEN.
Let me have three people in heaven. Go
to heaven.
Go under the earth.
And you guys are on earth. ARE WE
TOGETHER?
>> DO YOU KNOW WHAT THE BIBLE SAYS? IT LOOK
AT THIS. It says EVERY KNEE SHOULD BOW
OF THOSE IN HEAVEN AND OF THOSE ON EARTH
AND OF THOSE UNDER. SO THE BOWING IS
SIMULTANEOUS.
IT IS NOT THE HEAVENS BOW, THE EARTH BOW
AND THEN NO UH WHEN THAT NAME IS
MENTIONED THERE IS A BOWING IN ALL THE
THREE SPHERES IN HEAVEN. THERE IS A
BOWING. NOW NOW NO NOW I AM HERE. SO
THERE IS A HERALD. THE KING IS COMING.
THE KING IS COMING IN HIS MAJESTY. THE
TERRITORY KNOWS WHO THE KING IS. THE
HEAVENS KNOW WHO THE KING IS. THE EARTH
KNOW WHO THE KING IS. THEY'RE UNDER THE
EARTH. THE DEMONS, THE POWERS, THE
REBELLIOUS SPIRITS, THEY KNOW WHO THE
KING IS BECAUSE THERE IS ONLY ONE KING.
HIS NAME IS JESUS. SO WHEN THE HEROD AND
WHO IS THE HEROD?
WHO IS THE HEROD? WHO IS THE HEROD? IT
IS ME AND YOU. THAT'S WHY WE PRAY IN THE
NAME OF JESUS. WE DON'T CALL THE NAME IN
VAIN. WE ARE TRYING TO ANNOUNCE THE
AUTHORITY OF THE KING. SO WHEN WE BEGIN
TO DECLARE WHEN THE HERALD IS RUNNING
AND SAYING JESUS JESUS JESUS JESUS EVERY
KNEE BOWS BEFORE EVEN HE APPEARS BECAUSE
THERE IS AUTHORITY IN THE NAME THEY KNOW
WHO THE PERSON IS. IT IS NOT THE ONE
ANNOUNCING THAT CARRIES AUTHORITY. IT IS
THE NAME THAT CARRIES AUTHORITY. HE SAYS
YOU HAVE NOT BECAUSE YOU HAVE ASKED NOT.
BUT IN THE DAYS COMING WHEN YOU SHALL
ASK OF THE FATHER IN MY NAME. I DON'T
NEED TO BE THERE. WHEN THE DEMONS HEAR
MY NAME THEY KNOW WHAT TO DO. WHEN THE
POWERS IN THE REALMS OF THE EARTH WHEN
THEY HEAR MY NAME THEY KNOW WHAT TO DO.
WHEN THOSE THAT ARE IN THE HEAVENLIES
WHEN THEY HEAR MY NAME THEY KNOW WHAT TO
DO. THAT'S WHY THE BIBLE SAYS YOU WILL
LAY HANDS ON THE SICK. IN MY NAME YOU
SHALL CAST OUT DEVILS. IN MY NAME YOU
SHALL HEAL THE SICK. WHY? HE HE THAT
CAME AS A BONDERVANT. HE COULD BE
TRUSTED WITH THE POWER. HE CAME AS A
BONDERVANT HUMBLED HIMSELF UNTO DEATH.
HE QUALIFIED TO BEAR THE NAME. HE WAS
GIVEN THE NAME. THE NAME THAT IS ABOVE
EVERY OTHER NAME. ANYTHING THAT IS IN
THE REALM OF MAN HAS A NAME.
ANYTHING IN THE REALM OF MAN HAS A NAME.
CANCER IS A NAME. POVERTY IS A NAME.
CURSES IS A NAME. WHATEVER YOU ARE
LACKING, EVERYTHING HAS A NAME. BUT THE
BIBLE SAYS, THE BIBLE DOES NOT TELL US.
IT SAYS NOW THAT AT THE NAME OF JESUS,
EVERY KNEE SHOULD BOW. CANCER HAS
WHATEVER YOU ARE DEALING WITH, IT HAS A
NAME. IF SOMETHING HAS A NAME, IT HAS A
NEED.
IT SAYS AT THE MENTION OF THE NAME
JESUS, EVERY KNEE WILL BOW. PLEASE STAND
BECAUSE I WANT TO SHOW YOU THE AUTHORITY
WE CARRY IN CHRIST. IT IS NOT JUST
ANOTHER NAME. BY THIS REVELATION, THERE
ARE THINGS THAT ARE BEGINNING TO BOW. WE
ARE NOT HERE TO NEGOTIATE WITH THE
DEVIL. WE CAME FOR OUR TERRITORY. WE
CAME FOR OUR JOY. WE CAME FOR OUR
HEALING. WE CAME FOR OUR PEACE. WE CAME
FOR OUR OPEN DOOR. WE CAME FOR OUR
BREAKTHROUGHS. WE CAME FOR WHATEVER CAN
DELIVER IN THE NAME OF JESUS. IN THE
NAME OF JESUS. IN THE NAME OF JESUS.
THE KING HAS NOT APPEARED. THE KING WILL
APPEAR WHEN THE TRUMPET SOUNDS. BUT THE
NAME OF JESUS CARRIES THE AUTHORITY OF
THE HONOR OF THAT NAME.
>> HAVE YOU EVER SEEN PEOPLE READING
THEOLOGY OF the president? WHEN YOU
DON'T LISTEN TO THAT SPEECH, YOU ARE
DISRESPECTING THE PRESIDENT, NOT THE MAN
LISTENING. SO IF IF IF
A C CANNOT BOW, IT IS NOT DISRESPECTING
ME. IT IS A CONTENTION OF THE CURSE AND
THE NAME.
>> You you SEE OUR WORK IS EASIER. WE DON'T
HEAL THE SICK. WE CARRY A NAME THAT
HEALS THE SICK. YOU GO AND DO YOUR
BUSINESS. YOU GO TO THE HOSPITAL SAY IN
THE NAME OF JESUS BE HEALED. WHETHER
THEY GET HEALED OR NOT, IT HAS NOTHING
TO DO WITH YOU. YOU HAVE DONE YOUR PART.
YOU HAVE APPLIED THE NAME. LET THE KNEES
BOW. DO YOU KNOW WE NO LONGER EXERCISE
THAT NAME. WE WE ARE PERPETUALLY IN
WARFAIRS.
WE NO LONGER DEPLOY THE NAME. YOU YOU
YOU DON'T HEAR THE NAME SATAN MENTIONED
HERE. SOMEONE IS JUST RUNNING IN THE
TERRITORY. He's coming from THE KING. WE
WHEN WE GO TO PRAYER, WE ARE WITH THE
KING. THEM THAT DWELL IN THE SECRET
PLACE OF THE MOST HIGH. SO THERE ARE
THINGS WE HAVE HEARD FROM THE PLACE OF
PRAYER. SO WE ARE NOT COMING WITH A
RUMOR. WE ARE COMING WITH AN ASSURANCE.
THOU SAYS THE LORD. SO WHEN WE ARE
COMING FROM PRAYER, WE BEGIN TO MAKE
DECLARATIONS. WE MAKE OH MY GOD. THE
REALM OF PRAYER, THERE IS A REAL CALLED
INTIMACY. INTIMACY INTO ME. SEE LORD
CHECK MY HEART. TAKE CHECK MY ATTITUDE.
IF THERE BE ANYTHING THAT CAN HINDER ME
BUT FROM CARRYING YOUR AUTHORITY LET IT
BE DEALT WITH. IT'S NOT A PLACE OF
BREAD. IS A PLACE OF SAYING DADDY I'M
HERE. DADDY I'M HERE TO WORSHIP YOU TO
ADORE YOU TO GLORIFY YOU. I DO NOT HAVE
ANY OTHER FATHER. YOU ARE ALL THAT I
HAVE. I'M A BOND SERVANT. I HAVE
SURRENDERED MY RIGHT. I HAVE SURRENDERED
MY WILL. SPEAK TO ME LORD. THEN IN THAT
AREA YOU HEAR A WORD. BY THE TIME YOU
ARE COMING FROM PRAYER, REMEMBER HE HAS
ALREADY SPOKEN THROUGH HIS WORD. FOR THE
WORD YOU'RE GOING TO HEAR IS A
SCRIPTURE,
CAN I SURPRISE YOU? IS NOT AN EXTERNAL
SCRIPTURE.
THE SCRIPTURE DOES NOT COME FROM
OUTSIDE. YOU ARE THE ONE WHO READ IT
EXTERNALLY BECAUSE HE THAT IS IN ME, I
CARRY JESUS IN ME. SO WHEN I'M IN THE
PLACE OF COMMUNION, GUESS WHAT THE LORD
DOES? HE PULLS APART OF HIMSELF BECAUSE
IN THE BEGINNING WAS THE WORD AND THE
WORD WAS WITH GOD AND THE WORD OF GOD.
SO THE WORD IS IN ME. I HAVE GENESIS TO
IN REVELATION IN MY SPIRIT WHEN I BEGIN
TO COMMUNE WITH GOD. HE CAN PULL OUT
HABACOOK. HE CAN PULL OUT MATTHEW
BECAUSE THE WORD IS THE WORD FROM
GENESIS TO REVELATION. SO I AM NOT
LOOKING FOR A WORD TO READ. THE WORD IS
IN ME. THAT'S WHY WHEN I STAY WITH HIM,
HE BEGINS TO REVEAL WHAT IS IN ME. THE
BIBLE SAYS I CAN DO EXCEEDINGLY ABOVE
MORE THAN WHAT YOU CAN IMAGINE OR EVEN
THINK ACCORDING TO THE POWER THAT IS IN
ME.
>> The scripture IS IN YOU.
>> THE HOLY GHOST WILL PULL A VERSE. THAT
YOU HAVE NEVER READ. THEN THAT VERSE
MOVES FROM GRAPH BECAUSE YOU KNOW IT AS
A SCRIPTURE WRITTEN. IT MOVES FROM
GRAPHICS ON YOUR BIBLE. IT BECOMES
REMMA, A LIVING WORD. THE WORDS OF GOD
ARE NOT WRITTEN. THE WORDS OF GOD ARE
ALIVE. IT DEPENDS ON WHERE YOU ARE IN
LIFE. WHICH WORDS ARE YOU ENCOUNTERING?
BECAUSE THESE ARE LIVING WORDS. THAT
WORD BECOMES ALIVE. IT IS A LIVING WORD.
AND BECAUSE MY SPIRIT IS ALIVE, THERE IS
A COLLUSION NOW WITH THAT WHICH H WHICH
HAS BECOME ALIVE. And there is A
COLLUSION. THAT COLLUSION IS CALLED
CATALANO. MY SPIRIT NOW CAPTURES THE
WORD NOT AS REVELATION BUT AS REALITY
THAT CHANGES MY CIRCUMSTANCE.
THE GRAPH SAYS BY HIS STRIPES YOU ARE
HEALED. THAT'S GRAPH. YOU HAVE READ IT.
THEN SUDDENLY YOU'RE IN A BED HOSPITAL.
AN AMBULANCE is ratcheting you TO THE
HOSPITAL. THEN AS YOU ARE PRAYING IN
TONGUES, THE HOLY GHOST PULLS IT FROM
YOUR SPIRIT. BUT HE STRIPES YOUR HEAL
AND YOU DISCOVER ON THAT BED THAT WORD
HAS BECOME ALIVE. AS YOU ARE PRAYING IN
THE HOLY GHOST, YOUR SPIRIT NOW
CATALANOS. BY THE TIME IT KALAMANOS, THE
REALITY OF THAT WORD BEGINS TO BECOME
YOUR REALITY. AND THE VIRUS DIES, THE
BACTERIA DIES, THE FUNGI DIES.
BY THE TIME THEY TAKE YOU TO THE LAB,
THEY ARE NO LONGER CHECKING YOUR BLOOD.
THEY ARE CHECKING A CATALANO THAT IS NOW
FLOWING IN YOUR BLOOD. THE SYSTEM HAS
CHANGED. IT'S BEING ALIGNED TO ANOTHER
ORDER. THEY CAN SAY WHAT THEY WANT TO
SAY, BUT I CAN ASSURE YOU THIS IS A
REALITY.
Every knee shall bow.
>> Oh my god. are the mention of the name
Jesus. I give you the permission. I
don't know what NEEDS TO BOW BUT THIS IS
THE SERVICE. I SAY THIS IS THE SERVICE.
STUBBORN MATTERS.
THERE IS NOTHING THAT IS ABOVE THE NAME
OF JESUS. THIS IS THE NAME ABOVE EVERY
OTHER NAME. THE BIBLE SAYS THEY SHALL
CALL UPON THE NAME.
It does not say they will call upon THE
LORD. CALLING UPON THE LORD IS PRAYER.
>> CALLING UPON THE NAME OF THE LORD IS
REVELATION.
IT IS WHEN YOU BECOME A HERALD OF THE
REALITIES OF CALVARY. THEY SHALL CALL
UPON THE NAME OF THE LORD. THE NAME OF
THE LORD IS A STRONG TOWER.
IS A TOWER THE RIGHTEOUS RUN INTO IT.
JESUS,
IT IS A STRONG TOWER. THE RUSSIA RUN
INTO IT AND THEY ARE SAFE. I'M BELIEVING
GOD FOR SUPERNATURAL MATTERS TODAY
BECAUSE AT THE MENTION OF THAT NAME,
THEM THAT HAVE BEEN CAPTIVE MUST BE SET
FREE. AT THE MENTION OF THAT NAME, THERE
ARE KNIVES IN HELL THAT MUST BEGIN TO
BOW. THERE ARE POWERS IN DARKNESS,
WITCHCRAFT, WIZARDHOOD, FREE MERCENARY
OR CULTISM. POWERS OF DARKNESS IN THE
NAME OF JESUS. IN THE NAME OF JESUS. LET
THEM BOW.
I SEE THINGS BREAKING IN THE REALMS OF
THE SPIRIT. THERE IS FREEDOM. LIBERTY IS
COMING YOUR WAY. THINGS ARE BEGINNING TO
BOW. THINGS ARE BEGINNING TO BOW.
SOMEBODY OPEN UP YOUR MOUTH. INFLUENCE.
RELEASE THE NAME. CALL UPON THE NAME OF
THE LORD. CALL UPON THE NAME OF THE
LORD. CALL UPON THAT NAME.
JESUS,
every tongue in heaven AND EARTH SHALL
DECLARE your glory. EVERY KNEE MUST BOW
AT YOUR THRONE.
IN WORSHIP.
YOU'LL BE EXALTED. OH GOD,
YOUR KINGOM SHALL NOT PASS AWAY.
EVERY TONGUE UPON
THE NAME SHALL DECLARE YOUR GLORY. EVERY
KNEE SHALL BOW AT YOUR THR
in worship.
You'll be exalted,
oh God.
And your KINGOM SHALL NOT PASS AWAY.
I AM
EVERY
DIRECTION OF THE NAME OF JESUS
and your kingom.
Somebody's name we say Jesus.
SAY JESUS. JESUS.
JESUS.
EVERY
JESUS
EVERYTHING.
JESUS.
EVERY TIME EVERYBODY
HALLELUJAH.
HALLELUJAH. I WANT US to declare Jesus
SEVEN TIMES. I AM BELIEVING GOD FOR
SUPERNATURAL THINGS TO BEGIN TO HAPPEN
OVER YOUR LIFE. THE CAPTIVES WILL BE SET
FREE. YS ARE GOING TO BE BROKEN. I SEE
KNEES BOWING UNDER THE EARTH. EVERY
REBELLIOUS SPIRIT MUST BEGIN TO BOW
RIGHT NOW. I WISH I CAN HAVE A CHURCH
TODAY. I CAN'T EXPECT THEM TODAY. I
DON'T KNOW WHO IS IN THE HOUSE BUT AT
THE MENTION OF THE NAME JESUS AT THE
MENTION OF THE NAME JESUS EVERY KNEE
WILL BOW IN THE HEAVENS ON THE EARTH AND
EVEN UNDER THE EARTH AS WE ARE CALLING
UPON THIS NAME. LET THE SICK BE HEALED.
LET THEM THAT ARE BOUND BE DELIVERED.
LET BONDAGES BE TAKEN AWAY AT THE
MENTION OF THIS NAME. LET DOORS OPEN UP.
WHATEVER YOU ARE BELIEVING GOD FOR, LET
IT BEGIN TO HAPPEN OVER YOUR LIFE. I AM
SEEING A COVER OF AUTHORITY AND A COVER
OF THE SUPERNATURAL FALLING IN THIS
HOUSE. WE ARE GOING TO CALL HIM SEVEN
TIMES.
HALLELUJAH.
NUMBER ONE, SOMEBODY SAY JESUS.
>> JESUS.
>> NUMBER TWO, SOMEBODY SAY JESUS. JESUS.
NUMBER THREE, SOMEBODY SAY JESUS.
>> NUMBER FOUR, SOMEBODY SAY JESUS.
>> NUMBER FIVE, SOMEBODY SAY JESUS.
AS WE ARE DECLARING THE SECOND TIME, THE
POWER OF GOD IS GOING TO FALL OVER SOME
PEOPLE. THE ANOINTING, THE MANTLE, THE
ORDINATION, SOMETHING IS GOING TO MOVE.
THE REAL OF THE SPIRIT IS GOING TO OPEN
UP THE SEVEN TIME. SOMEBODY DECLARE
JESUS.
RECEIVE IT NOW. LET THE POWER, LET THE
ANOINTING, LET THE AUTHORITY, LET THE
POWER, LET IT COME UPON YOU. TAKE IT.
LET IT IN THE NAME OF JESUS. TAKE IT IN
THE NAME OF JESUS. LET THE SICK BE
HEALED. LET EYES OPEN. LET THEIR EARS
OPEN.
RECREATION. RECEIVE THE ANOINTING.
Receive the authority.
Jesus.
WE CALL HIM JESUS.
YEAH.
JESUS,
WHAT'S HIS NAME? JESUS, we're calling on
the name.
We're calling on THE NAME.
WE'RE calling on the NAME
JESUS.
My Jesus
say EVERY
child pass away.
Oh, BECAUSE YOUR NAME IS THE HIGHEST.
YOUR NAME IS THE GREATEST. YOUR NAME
STAND.
Your name
Jesus.
YOUR NAME IS
ABOVE ALL
your name.
One more time. SAY YOUR NAME. YOUR NAME.
SAY YOUR IS THE GREATEST. Say your name
above all.
Jesus.
Your name.
>> Hallelujah.
SOMEBODY CELEBRATE THE LORD.